<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&apos;m Azizul Wahid!</title>
    <description>I&apos;m an experienced Software and Data Engineer. I specialize in cloud computing and data engineering technologies.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 19:40:31 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 19:40:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-tech-journey&quot;&gt;My Tech Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-spark&quot;&gt;The Spark&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, my passion for software engineering ignited in a third-year Physics lab at the University of California Santa Barbara. While programming to analyze celestial phenomena, I discovered an equal—if not greater—thrill in writing lines of code. The analytical mindset nurtured through my Physics studies has been invaluable in my software engineering career, equipping me with a unique problem-solving perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crafting-solutions&quot;&gt;Crafting Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What truly excites me about being in tech is crafting solutions that make an impact. I’ve designed cloud-based content delivery networks and implemented real-time query solutions, all utilizing the power of AWS services. Each project has been a lesson in efficiency, innovation, and pushing boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-engineering&quot;&gt;Data Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing data is like solving a complex puzzle with ever-changing pieces. I’ve built robust data pipelines, optimized data retrieval in warehouses, and fine-tuned performance—each requiring a meticulous attention to detail. I pride myself on implementing solutions that are not only technically sound but also business-efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-growing-toolkit&quot;&gt;A Growing Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hunger for learning is ceaseless. While I began my journey focusing mainly on Python and AWS, I’ve since expanded my skills to include data engineering technologies like Snowflake and Apache Kafka. Most recently, I’ve started learning JavaScript, adding another dimension to my skill set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sharing-knowledge&quot;&gt;Sharing Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this fast-paced industry, sharing experiences and best practices is crucial. I’ve been fortunate enough to contribute to project demos, providing insights into effective data management and software engineering strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beyond-the-screen&quot;&gt;Beyond the Screen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m not deep in code, I’m underwater exploring new depths while diving, scaling heights through rock climbing, or traveling through the worlds encapsulated in books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-connect&quot;&gt;Let’s Connect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s for a project, potential collaboration, or just a chat about tech, diving, or books, I’m just an email away. Reach out to me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:azzlwahid@gmail.com&quot;&gt;azzlwahid@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or take a glance at my GitHub for my latest endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 23:04:23 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
